MONYEM EMMANUEL ONUWA

19 Kenneth Close, off Balogun S. Fayowole Street, Awoyaya - Parapo, Lagos. **TEL**: +234 (0) 7037288781.

E-mail: monyememmanuel.ng@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF WORK EXPERIENCE:

Certified Project Management Professional, with a career experience across fields in the Oil and Gas industry. These include Subsea engineering, structural & design engineering and project management. Having been trained and thereafter worked as a subsea structural design engineer at Marine Platforms Limited (MPL), SAIPEM, I have gained sound knowledge of the codes and standards used in the industry and, worked with recommended practices/specification from IOCs like CHEVRON, SNEPCo, SPDC (DEP), TOTAL (GSP) etc. I have worked as a Company Site Representative (CSR) at AVEON OFFSHORE, MUDIAME INTERNATIONAL LIMITED etc., where I did general management and control of quality of fabrication/construction works in the project.

Adept at structural design software like AUTOCAD, SOLIDWORKS, SACS, STAADPRO, I have made remarkable contributions in companies I have worked with in delivering perfect job, timely and safely to our clients.

My deep passion in software engineering, has geared me into training students for over one year web development – frontend and backend, with special interest in frontend web development.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- ✓ BOSIET/CA-EBS CERTIFIED.
- ✓ IPMP CERTIFIED.
- ✓ HSE LEVEL 11 CERTIFED.
- ✓ STAADPRO CERTIFIED.
- ✓ SACS CERTIFIED.
- ✓ AUTOCAD CERTIFIED.
- ✓ SUPPLY CHAIN AND LOGISTICS
- ✓ SOLIDWORKS CERTIFIED

OTHER SKILLS:

- ✓ Coding and Web Development
- ✓ Microsoft Office
- ✓ Microsoft Project
- ✓ Leadership & Management
- ✓ Negotiation & Communication skills

KEY PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN:

- ✓ SPDC LIMITED/SUNLINK JV (HI FEED) Design and analysis of offshore structures like Jacket Topsides, Lifting analysis of Flare structures, Transportation analysis of Topsides and Jackets.
- ✓ TOTAL/PREOWEI FEED Design and analysis of offshore structures like FLET, In-line Tees in accordance with company's design basis and premise.
- ✓ SOUTHERN SALES GAS EVACUATION PIPELINE PROJECT(SHELL/SAIDEL) Project engineer over the design and fabrication of SSGEP 16" spools for gas transportation.
- ✓ TOTAL/EGINA PROJECT (TOTAL UPSPREAM) Detailed structural analysis of jumpers used for crude transportation using structural analysis software.
- ✓ MEJI PROJECT (CHEVRON) Engineering, Structural model and analysis of both topside and subsea riser clamps for meji jackets. Involved in the installation of riser clamps and flexible flowline at Meji Field for CHEVRON.
- ✓ SNEPCo IRM (BONGA FIELD) Project Engineer coordinating engineering operations at Bonga field, offshore, during the installation of B68 jumper and B35 Christmas tree among other operations.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

GRANDEUR TECH AND IT SOLUTION, JULY; 2022 – TILL DATE. RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ✓ Training complete beginners the basis of web development.
- Training students across different cohorts on front end web development stacks HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, etc.
- ✓ Day to day follow up on students to perform their tasks.
- Responding to student's questions both online and physical classroom condition.

OFFSHORE STRUCTURAL ENGINEER, SAIPEM CONTRACTING NIGERIA LIMITED, AUG; 2019 - TILL DATE.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ✓ Structural Modelling & Analysis of subsea structures like FLET, In-Line Tees, T-FLET, Manifolds, Lateral Buckling Mitigation Systems, etc.
- Involved in the development of installation procedures for subsea structures.
- ✓ Rigging selection & Designs.
- Design and analysis of lifting plans for both offshore and onshore lifting operations
- Supervision of fabricators to ensure compliance with structure's design premise and basis.

PROJECT/STRUCTURAL ENGINEER, MARINE PLATFORMS LIMITED, OCT; 2017 - MAY; 2019. **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- ✓ Structural Modelling & Analysis.
- ✓ Sea fastening analysis & Deck Planning.
- ✓ Involved in the development of installation procedures for subsea components.
- ✓ Rigging selection & Designs.
- ✓ Design and analysis of lifting plans for both offshore and onshore lifting operations
- ✓ Mobilization and demobilization activities on several vessels.
- ✓ Developing tender documents.

AVEON OFFSHORE, PORT-HARCOURT.

Company Site Representatives, CSR. (SPOOL FABRICATION), April 2018.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

- ✓ Monitoring and recording of welding procedure qualification test (WPQT).
 ✓ Analyzing the Mechanical results on a welding procedure test (Tensile, Micro etch, hardness, Impact) with standard documents.
- Monitoring of Welders Qualifications Test (WQT).
- ✓ Conducting of visual inspection on welded joints, daily weld and inspection records of fit up & Weld ioint.
- Monitoring of joint fit-up and final Dimensional checkup before the inception of welding.
- ✓ Monitor the usage of welding process and process parameters in accordance with the WPS.
- ✓ Material inspection and Traceability.

MUDIAME INTERNATIONAL LIMITED, PORT-HARCOURT.

Company Site Representatives, CSR. (MECHANICAL TESTING) April 2018

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Destructive tensile test on coupons for spool fabrication.

INSTRUCTOR, TECHNICAL COLLEGE, AGBOR, DELTA STATE, 2015 - 2016 **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- ✓ Tutored engineering material selection.
- ✓ Any other duty assigned to me by my superior.

LECTURER, BENUE STATE UNIVERSITY, 2013-2014.

Department of Refrigeration and Airconditioning. **RESPONSIBILITIES:**

- ✓ Lectured students at 200 and 400 level
- Prepared examination questions and detailed marking scheme.

✓ Any other duty assigned to me by my Head of Department.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

INSTITUTION	QUALIFICATION	DATE
Delta State University, Abraka.	B. Eng. Mechanical, Metallurgical and Production Engineering. (Second Class Honours: Upper Division).	2008-2012
Umutu Mixed Secondary School, Umutu.	SSCE	1998-2003
Ethiope Primary School, Umutu.	FSLC	1992-1998

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

INSTITUTION	QUALIFICATION	DATE
International project Management Professionals (IPMP)	Certified Project Manager (CPM)	April, 2014
Joint Professional Training and Support Int'l	Health Safety and Environment (HSE 2)	July, 2014
Falck Prime Atlantic	Basic Offshore Safety Induction Emergency Training (BOSIET)	January, 2018
Falck Prime Atlantic	Compressed Air Emergency Breathing System (CA-EBS)	January, 2018
Tom Associates	Supply Chain and Logistics Management.	October, 2018
Lonadek, Cedar Centre	Entrepreneurship	October, 2018
Marine Platforms Limited	Project/Subsea Structural Engineer	November, 2018

AWARD/SCHOLARSHIP

✓ Chevron Agbami scholarship, 2009.

The scholarship covered my entire bills throughout my university education since my CGPA always exceeded the minimum criteria for the scholarship sustenance.

HOBBIES

✓ Counselling, Researching and Public Speaking.

REFEREE

Available on request.